<Publish>
	<!--Id must be set in order to update existed mod. it is not required for publishing mod for the first time-->
	<ModId Value="96619" />
	<!--Name of the mod to display to players-->
	<DisplayName Value="Trips View" />
	<!--Short description of the mod-->
	<ShortDescription Value="Adds graphs with different trips information statistics" />
	<!--Long description of the mod. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<!--LongDescription Value="This is a long description" /-->
	<LongDescription>
This mod adds a few graphs showing information about the trips that cims take. These include: transit passengers per hour, trips purpose per hour, and commute times information. The menu with these options can be accessed by clicking on the magnifying glass icon on the top left.

## Mode Shares

This panel has two tables: linked trips and unlinked trips.

* **Linked Trips:** These are complete trips from the origin to the destination including transfers. The modes shows are Vehicle, Transit, and Walk.
* **Unlinked Transit Trips:** This table has the sum of total number of boardings on each transit vehicle, grouped by mode (Bus, Tram, Subway, Train, Ship and Airplane)

This panel also has the information of the average number of transfers for each passenger, shown at the bottom.

## Transit Hourly Passengers

This graph shows the number of passengers in each transit mode (bus, tram, subway, train, ship and airplane) by hour. When this mod is first loaded in a city, data will be collected every hour and incrementally added to the plot.

## Transit Waiting Time Frequency Distribution

Frequency distribution of waiting time for each transit mode.

## Passenger Kilometers Travelled (PKT)

Passenger-kilometers is the total distance travelled by all the passengers. PKT allows fair comparisons between different modes by considering both ridership and distance. For example, a bus system with 10,000 riders traveling short distances may have a lower PKT than a rail system with fewer riders traveling longer distances.

## Trips Purpose

Trip purposes is classified in four categories which are explained below. The number of trips by type is collected from the game every hour and the plot is summarized at midnight pm (game time) amd represents the whole day that just passed. When you load this mod for the first time in a city, you need to wait for a whole day to pass to be able to see this graph.

* **Home Based Work:** This include trips from Home to Work and from Work to Home.
* **Home Based School:** This include trips from Home to School and School to Home.
* **Home Based Other:** This consists of trips that start or end at home and go to or are from anyplace that is **not** work or school. This will include trips from home to shopping or leisure.
* **Non Home Based:** All trips that don't have home as the origin or destination.

## Commute Time Frequency Distribution

Frequency distribution of commute time for workers and categorized by education level. The data is grouped in 10 minute bins the label shown on the bin represents the start of that bin. For example, bin 10 represents trips that took between 10 and 19 minutes.

## Credits
* This mod was based on the Info Loom mod by Bruceyboy24804
	</LongDescription>
	<!--Thumbnail-->
	<Thumbnail Value="Properties/TripsView.png" />
	<!--Screenshot, can be set multiple times-->
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/transit.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/trippurpose.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/commute.png" />
	<Screenshot Value="Properties/Screenshots/modesharewaiting.png" />
	<!--Tag, can be set multiple times-->
	<Tag Value="" />
	<!--Link to the forum post where the mod can be discussed-->
	<ForumLink Value="https://forum.paradoxplaza.com/forum/threads/trips-view-mod.1720582/" />
	<!--Version of the mod-->
	<ModVersion Value="0.3.1" />
	<!--Recommended version of the base game to use the mod-->
	<GameVersion Value="1.2.*" />
	<!--Dependency for the mod, can be set multiple times-->
	<Dependency Id="" />
	<!--Change log for new version. Single line or multi line. Supports minimal markdown subset-->
	<ChangeLog>
* Disabled save of temporary data during auto-saves
	</ChangeLog>
	<!--External link. supported types are discord, github, youtube, twitch, x, paypal, patreon, buymeacoffee, kofi, crowdin, gitlab-->
	<ExternalLink Type="github" Url="https://github.com/ruzbeh0/TripsDataView" />
	<ExternalLink Type="discord" Url="https://discord.com/channels/1024242828114673724/1317339995413024860" />
	<ExternalLink Type="paypal" Url="https://www.paypal.com/paypalme/ruzbeh0" />
	<ExternalLink Type="kofi" Url="https://ko-fi.com/ruzbeh0" />
</Publish>